Lucy Zhu

CS Student @ Stanford website: <u>lzhu21.github.io</u>

With a focus on artificial intelligence and computer graphics, I am interested in the intersection of technology and design such as XR with my skills consisting of writing software and designing graphics. I have working experience with virtual reality and deep neural networks.

Education

Stanford University 2017-21

BS in Computer Science GPA: 3.688

Skills

CS: Python, Java, C++, C, C#

Design: Unity, Unreal, Maya, 3DS Max, Adobe Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Indesign

Public Service

- **Media Team** Students for a Sustainable Stanford Sept 2018 – June 2019
- Financial Officer Intern Girls Teaching Girls to Code Sept 2017 – June 2018
- **Public Relations Co-Chair** Stanford Vietnamese Student Association
 Sept 2017 June 2019

Work Experience

Research Intern - Stanford Vision/AI Department (Summer 2019)

- worked under Prof. Leonidas J Guibas to research about application of deep learning towards analyzing 3D models
- designed and implemented a pioneering CNN in Python to answer questions about 3D point cloud models
- demonstrated the feasibility of solving the counting problem given the appropriate part labels with a peak accuracy of 95.7%

Programmer - Virtual Human Interaction Lab (Sept 2018 - June 2019)

- cooperated in a team to implement the cross-platform structure of 1000 Cuts, a project we focused on, to port it from Unity to Unreal
- established the workflow and logic of videos for 1000 Cuts
- wrote C++ and C# scripts to implement interactivity within simulations including avatar movement and object manipulation

Image Developer - Stanford University (June 2018 - Dec 2018)

- worked in a team to deploy Mac, Windows, and Linux images on machines throughout the campus via Python scripts
- wrote scripts ranging from bash aliases to running multiple processes that sped up workflow and contributed towards deploying the OS image several weeks in advance of the projected date
- working in a fast-paced environment had effective communication, operating machines remotely in a Linux environment, and efficiency be priorities I developed to fulfill the numerous daily technical issues reported via a ticketing system

Freelance Artist/Illustrator (2013 - present)

- set a timetable of art commissions arranged on Tumblr, Twitter, and Instagram
- exercised effective communication to achieve customer satisfaction

Projects

Computer Graphics and Imaging – 3 projects for Computer Graphics classes

- first project made it into top 10 images of class and got my raytraced image displayed on the class website: CS148 2018 Showcase
- used OpenGL, pbrt, and raytracing to create a computer-generated image
- programmed in C++ using Visual Studio

Graphic Novel Project (Sept 2018 - April 2019)

- collaborated to write and publish the graphic novel, *Flying Kites*, about the 2013 California Prison Hunger Strike
- designed the protagonist of the novel and delivered pitches for the plot
- planned and drew the storyboards for scenes in the book

1972 XA - Summer Science Program (Summer 2016)

- selective five-week research program hosted at New Mexico Institute of Technology by MIT and Caltech
- collaborated in a team of three to track and evaluate the 1972 XA's (asteroid) orbit
- utilized a combination of Python, physics, and calculus skills to analyze potential orbit paths